( THUNDEROUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
" JONATHAN : " The Diary of Jonathan Harker .
" Third Of May , 1885 . "
" At last my long journey is drawing to its close . "
" What the eventual end will be , I cannot foresee . "
" But whatever may happen , I can rest secure "
" that I will have done all in my power to achieve success . "
" The last lap of my journey from the village of Klausenburg "
" proved to be more difficult than I had anticipated "
" due to the reluctance on the part of the coach driver to take me all the way . "
" However , as there was no other transport available , "
" I was forced to travel the last few kilometers on foot "
" before arriving at Castle Dracula . "
" The castle appeared innocuous enough in the warm afternoon sun , "
" and all seemed normal but for one thing . There were no birds singing . "
" As I crossed the wooden bridge and entered the gateway , "
" it suddenly seemed to become much colder "
" due , no doubt , to the icy waters of the mountain torrent I had just crossed . "
" However , I deemed myself lucky to have secured this post "
" and did not intend to falter in my purpose . "
( DOOR CREAKS OPEN )
( DOOR CREAKS SHUT )
( SOFT , EERIE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( CLOCK TICKING )
( SINISTER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
I 'm sorry . I didn 't hear you come in .
My name 's Jonathan Harker . I 'm the new librarian .
You will help me , won 't you ?
Say you will , please !
- How can I help you ? - Get me away from here .
- But why ? - He is keeping me prisoner .
Who is ? Count Dracula ?
I 'm afraid I don 't understand .
Oh , please . Please help me to escape !
( OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
Mr Harker , I am glad that you have arrived safely .
Count Dracula ?
I am Dracula . And I welcome you to my house .
I must apologise for not being here to greet you personally
but I trust you 've found everything you needed .
Thank you , sir . It was most thoughtful .
It was the least I could do after such a journey .
Yes , it is a long journey .
And tiring for you , no doubt . Permit me to show you to your room .
Thank you , sir .
DRACULA : No , please , allow me .
Unfortunately , my housekeeper is away at the moment .
- A family bereavement . You understand ? - Yes , of course .
DRACULA : However , I think you will find
that everything has been prepared for your comfort .
JONATHAN : How soon may I start work , sir ?
DRACULA : As soon as you wish . There are a large number of volumes to be indexed .
Is there anything else you require , Mr Harker ?
No , I don 't think so . You 've been very kind .
On the contrary , it is entirely my privilege .
I consider myself fortunate to have found such a distinguished scholar to act as my librarian .
I like quiet and seclusion .
This house , I think , offers that .
Then we are both satisfied . An admirable arrangement .
Oh , there is just one more thing , Mr Harker .
I have to go out and I will not be back until after sundown tomorrow .
Until then , please look upon this house as your own .
- Good night , Mr Harker . - Good night , sir .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
As I shall be away for so long ,
I think it 's better that you should have the key of the library , Mr Harker .
Thank you .
You will find the library to the left of the hall .
- May I ? - Yes , certainly .
DRACULA : Your wife ? JONATHAN : No , my fiancée .
DRACULA : You are a very fortunate man , Mr Harker .
May I ask her name ?
Lucy . Lucy Holmwood .
- Charming , charming . - You are very kind .
Good night .
Sleep well , Mr Harker .
( DOOR LOCKING )
JONATHAN : " At last I have met Count Dracula . "
" He accepts me as a man who has agreed "
" to work among his books , as I intended . "
" It only remains for me now to await the daylight hours "
" when , with God 's help , " .
" I will forever end this man 's reign of terror . "
( THUNDEROUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( SOFT , OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( DOOR SHUTS LOUDLY )
- Mr Harker , you will help me ? - If it 's at all possible .
But tell me why is Count Dracula keeping you prisoner ?
- I cannot tell you that . - But if I am to help you , I must know .
I 'm sorry , it 's not possible .
You make it very difficult for me .
After all , I am a guest here . If I 'm to help you I must have a reason .
A reason . You ask for a reason !
Is it not reason enough that he keeps me locked up in this house ,
holds me against my will ?
You can have no idea what an evil man he is !
Or what terrible things he does !
I could not , dare not try to leave on my own .
He would find me again , I know .
But with you to help me , I would have a chance .
You must help me ! You must ! You 're my only hope ! You must !
I 'll help you , I promise .
Oh !
( SOBS )
Please don 't distress yourself .
Thank you .
( OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( HISSES )
( WOMAN SCREAMS )
( JONATHAN CHOKING )
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
( CLIMACTIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
" JONATHAN : " I have become a victim of Dracula and the woman in his power .
" It may be that I am doomed to be one of them . "
" If that is so , I can only pray "
" that whoever finds my body "
" will possess the knowledge "
" to do what is necessary "
" to release my soul . "
" I have lost a day . Soon it will be dark . "
" While my senses are still my own , I must do what I set out to do . "
" I must find the resting place of Dracula "
" and , there , end his existence forever . "
" Soon it will be sundown and they will walk again . "
" I do not have much time . "
( DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( WOMAN SCREAMS )
( GASPS )
( SUSPENSEFUL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( STAKE CLATTERS )
( LIGHT-HEARTED MUSIC-BOX MUSIC PLAYS )
( DOOR OPENS )
( SWITCHES OFF MUSIC )
- Good day , sir . - Good day .
- May I have a brandy , please ? - Certainly , sir .
- Travelling far ? - VAN HELSING : Not much farther , I hope .
- Is it possible to have a meal ? - Yes , sir .
Inga !
Only a simple one , I 'm afraid , sir .
- Your change , sir . - Thank you .
We don 't get many travellers in these parts . Not that stop , anyway .
You had one a few days ago , I believe . A Mr Harker .
- Harker , sir ? - Yes .
He 's a friend of mine .
- He wrote to me from this address . - Not here , sir .
I remember the gentleman . He gave me a letter to post .
Hold your tongue , girl !
Was this the letter ?
- I 'm not sure . - Perhaps you remember the name .
Dr Van Helsing .
I 'm not sure .
Go and prepare a meal for this gentleman . At once . Do you hear me ?
What are you afraid of ?
- I don 't understand you . - Why all these garlic flowers ?
And over the window ?
And up here ?
They 're not for decoration , are they ?
- I don 't know what you 're talking about . - I think you do .
And I think you know something about my friend .
He came here with a purpose , to help you .
We haven 't asked for any help .
You need it all the same .
Look , sir , you 're a stranger here in Klausenburg .
Some things are best left alone ,
such as interfering in things which are beyond our powers .
Please don 't misunderstand me .
This is more than a superstition . I know . The danger is very real .
If the investigation that Mr Harker and I are engaged upon is successful
not only you , but the whole world will benefit .
VAN HELSING : Castle Dracula is somewhere here in Klausenburg .
Will you tell me how I get there ?
You ordered a meal , sir . As an innkeeper , it is my duty to serve you .
When you have eaten , I ask you to go and leave us in peace .
Your meal will be ready in a minute , sir , if you 'd like to take a seat .
Thank you .
This was found at the crossroads near that place .
He told me to burn it .
But your friend was such a nice gentleman , I couldn 't .
Harker ?
Harker !
( SINISTER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( CLIMACTIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( METAL CLINKING )
I 'm sorry , Mr Holmwood , but I really can not tell you anything more about how he died .
Can not or will not ?
Whichever you wish .
Dr Van Helsing , I am not at all satisfied .
You suddenly appear and tell us that Jonathan Harker is dead .
Yet you will not tell us where or how he died .
- I find it extremely suspicious . - Arthur !
- You have the death certificate . - Yes . Signed by you .
When did he die , Doctor ?
- 10 days ago , Mrs Holmwood . - 10 days ago !
- Where was he buried ? - He was cremated .
- By whose authority ? - His own .
As his friend and colleague , he told me some time ago that he would wish it .
You must know that Jonathan was going to marry my sister Lucy .
Surely you could have written .
I felt it would have been less of a shock if I came and told her personally .
I would rather you didn 't see my sister .
My wife and I will tell her .
Very well . I 'm sorry .
Will you please express my sympathy to Miss Lucy ?
If she wishes to get in touch with me , I am at her service .
Oh , Gerda , Dr Van Helsing is leaving . Will you show him to the door ?
Yes , sir .
Good day . Sir .
Why all this secrecy ? Why wouldn 't he tell us ?
Darling , Dr Van Helsing is a very eminent man .
Whatever his motives , you can be sure he had a good reason for them .
In any case , we can 't help poor Jonathan now .
Lucy is the one we must think of .
Is she well enough to be told ?
- It will be a terrible blow for her . - She must know sometime .
We won 't disturb her afternoon rest . We 'll see how she is this evening .
Jonathan will be home soon , I know it . Then I 'll get better , you 'll see .
I won 't be a trouble to Dr Seward or any of you .
Lucy , you 're no trouble to anyone . Now rest , get some sleep .
You 've got to get some colour back into those cheeks .
- Good night , Lucy . - Good night , Mina .
Good night , Arthur .
( SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
- MINA : Sleep well . - I 'll try .
( EERIE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( FOREBODING INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
HELSING : ( ON GRAMOPHONE ) Research on vampires .
Certain basic facts established .
One , light .
The vampire allergic to light .
Never ventures forth in the daytime .
Sunlight , fatal . Repeat , fatal .
Would destroy them .
Two , garlic .
Vampires repelled by odor of garlic .
Memo . Check final arrangements with Harker before he leaves for Klausenburg .
Three , the crucifix .
Symbolizing the power of good over evil .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
The power of the crucifix in these cases ...
Come in .
- You rang , sir ? - Oh , yes .
I want this letter delivered first thing in the morning .
- Will you see to that ? - Yes .
- Thank you . - Thank you , sir .
Anything the matter ?
What is it ?
To tell you the truth , when I was outside , I thought I heard you talking to someone .
Of course you did . I was talking to myself . You won 't forget that letter , will you ?
No , sir .
Yes .
HELSING : ( ON GRAMOPHONE ) The power of the crucifix in these cases is two-fold .
It protects the normal human being ,
but reveals the vampire or victim
of this vile contagion when in advanced stages .
Established that victims consciously detest being dominated by vampirism
but are unable to relinquish the practice ,
similar to addiction to drugs .
Ultimately , death results from loss of blood .
But , unlike normal death , no peace manifests itself
for they enter into the fearful state of the undead .
Since the death of Jonathan Harker , Count Dracula ,
the propagator of this unspeakable evil , has disappeared .
He must be found and destroyed .
( DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( CLIMACTIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
- She seems so much weaker , Doctor . - It 's a puzzling case , Mrs Holmwood .
The symptoms are those of anemia and I 'm treating her for this .
It can be a slow process , of course .
I had hoped for more encouraging signs by now .
- Please may I see Auntie Lucy ? - Not today , Tania .
- Is she very ill ? - I 'm afraid so .
- Do you know what 's wrong with her ? - Of course I do .
Then why don 't you make her better ?
Tania . Tania !
How many times have I told you not to go bothering Mrs Holmwood ?
- I 'm sorry , ma 'am . - That 's all right , Gerda .
- A child 's logic can be most disconcerting . - Yes .
Would you like a second opinion , Mrs Holmwood ?
Thank you , Doctor . I 'll think about it .
Well , carry on with the medicine and diet I 've prescribed
- and plenty of fresh air . - Yes , Doctor , I will .
MINA : Good day to you . SEWARD : Good day .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
Come in .
Mrs Holmwood , how very good of you to come .
- Please , will you sit down ? - Thank you .
You mentioned in your letter some things of Jonathan 's .
Yes , I have them ready . I would have brought them myself , but ...
Oh , I do understand . But you must appreciate Mr Holmwood was very upset .
Of course .
I only wish I could have been more helpful .
How did Miss Lucy take the news ?
We haven 't told her yet . Oh , she 's ill , very ill .
I 'm sorry to hear that . May I ask what 's the matter with her ?
It was all so sudden . It happened about 10 days ago .
Our family doctor says it 's anaemia .
But I 'm very unhappy about it .
Oh , I have nothing against Dr Seward , please don 't think that , but ...
- He did say I could have a second opinion . - I 'd like to see her at once .
- Oh ! I 'd be so grateful . - If you 'll excuse me .
MINA : Lucy , I 've brought someone to see you .
Dr Van Helsing . He 's a friend of Jonathan 's .
Miss Lucy .
What lovely flowers .
Jonathan 's dead , isn 't he ?
- It 's true , isn 't it ? - I 'm sorry .
- MINA : Did Arthur tell you ? - Nobody told me . I just knew .
- Is that why Dr Helsing is here ? - Partly .
Dr Helsing is a specialist . He 's come to help you .
Jonathan has told me so many things about you .
- Well , nice things , I hope . - Very nice .
Now , let 's see .
Mmm-hmm .
And here .
Now don 't you worry , we 'll soon have you well again .
Good bye , Doctor .
I 'm sorry you had a wasted journey , about Jonathan , I mean .
It wasn 't wasted , I promise you . Good day , Miss Lucy .
How could she have known of Jonathan 's death ?
- A premonition . It 's not uncommon . - But she took it so calmly , it worries me .
I 'm afraid there are more urgent things to worry about .
Those marks on her neck , when did they first appear ?
I noticed them first shortly after she became ill .
I asked her about them . She said she thought she had been stung .
Well , it is quite possible , of course .
Dr Seward said she must have plenty of fresh air . Her windows are open all the time .
Between the hours of sunset and sunrise , all the windows in her room ,
with the possible exception of a small fanlight for ventilation , must be kept shut .
- Oh , but Dr Seward said ... - Mrs Holmwood ,
you called me in for a second opinion .
If I am to help your sister-in-law , there are certain things you must do to help me ,
however unorthodox they may appear .
- Yes , I know , but ... - Madam ...
If you love Miss Lucy , be guided by me , I beg you .
I 'll do anything to make her well again .
Now , you must get some garlic flowers , as many as you can .
Place them by her windows , and her door and by her bedside .
They may be taken out during the day , but under no circumstances ,
even if the patient implores you , must they be removed at night .
I cannot impress upon you strongly enough
how important it is that you obey my instructions .
Do exactly as I say and we may be able to save her .
If you don 't , she will die .
I 'll be here in the morning .
( LUCY MOANING )
( PANTING )
( MOANING )
( VASE SHATTERS )
Heavens , child ! What is it ?
Oh , Gerda . These flowers , I can 't stand them !
They do smell strongly , but Mrs Holmwood said ...
I don 't care what she said ! Please , take them away ! Please !
Well ...
Oh , please , Gerda , they stifle me .
All right , miss , I 'll take them out .
And the windows , you 'll open the windows ?
Yes , Miss Lucy , if that 's what you want .
I 'll come back for the rest .
( FOREBODING INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
There was nothing I could do to save her .
- ( KNOCKING ON DOOR ) - ( DOOR OPENS )
SEWARD : Doctor Van ...
Mrs Holmwood , did you do as I told you ?
She did . And you have seen the result .
- But , Arthur ... - Please , sir . Excuse me , sir .
It was all my fault . She could not breathe . She looked so ill .
She begged me to open the windows and throw away all the plants .
Oh , I know you told me not to , ma 'am , but ...
Gerda , what time was this ?
It was about midnight .
- I heard a noise ... - ARTHUR : All right , Gerda .
- You may go now . - Yes , sir . Thank you , sir .
Oh , I am so sorry , sir .
Whatever happened , all I know is that you have brought us nothing but grief .
First Jonathan , and now Lucy .
Whoever you are and whatever your motives , please go and leave us in peace .
Mr Holmwood , when I told you about Jonathan ,
I thought it better for your peace of mind to spare the details
of the dreadful circumstances in which he died .
But the tragic death of your sister is so closely linked with Jonathan 's
that I think you should now know the truth .
I can 't expect you to believe me , but you will , I know , believe Jonathan .
Here are his last words . His diary .
When you have read it , you will understand .
ARTHUR : Well , what is it , Gerda ?
It 's a policeman , sir . He 's got Tania with him .
Tania ?
- Show him in , Gerda . - Very good , sir .
- Good evening , ma 'am . Good evening , sir . - What is it , officer ?
I found this little girl , here . She was very distressed indeed .
- Tell them what you told me . - I don 't want to .
Oh ...
Tania !
There 's no need to be frightened .
Now , come on over here , sit with me , and tell me all about it .
Oh .
Now , you don 't want Mr Holmwood to think you 're a crybaby , do you ?
You 're a big girl now .
Now , come on . Tell me what happened .
Well , I was out by myself , and she came up to me .
And she said , " Hello , Tania , shall we go for a little walk ? "
And I said yes . And we went for a walk .
Then someone came along , and she ran away and left me
and I was lost .
Who was she ? Who did you see ?
Come on . Tell me .
Who was she ?
Aunt Lucy .
( DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( FOREBODING INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
- I heard you call me , Aunt Lucy . - Yes , dear .
Come along .
You 're cold . Where are we going ?
For a little walk . I know somewhere nice and quiet where we can play .
Is it much further , Aunt Lucy ? I 'm so tired .
We 're nearly there , my darling .
Lucy !
Arthur , dear brother !
Dear Arthur , why didn 't you come sooner ?
Come , let me kiss you .
( GASPING )
( SCREAMING )
Put this on .
- Please , I want to go home . - And so you shall .
I 'll just go and fetch Mr Holmwood and then we can all go home together .
- Not Aunt Lucy . - No , not Aunt Lucy . Now you sit here .
Be a good girl . There .
You look like a teddy bear now . Will you wear this pretty thing ?
There . Isn 't that lovely ?
- Now , you promise not to run away ? - I promise .
Good . Now , look ,
if you watch over there , you 'll see the sun come up .
Keep warm .
You understand now ?
- But why Lucy ? - Because of Jonathan .
You read my note in his diary about the woman he found at Klausenburg .
This is Dracula 's revenge .
- Lucy is to replace that woman . - Oh , no !
I 've watched her tomb each night since she was interred three days ago .
Tonight she ventured out for the first time .
Holmwood , I know your one wish is that Lucy should rest in peace .
I promise to fulfill that wish . But , first ,
if I have your consent , she can lead us to Dracula .
How can you suggest such a thing ?
That she should be possessed by this evil for another second ?
And what about Gerda 's child out there , and the others she will defile ?
Oh , no , I couldn 't ! I couldn 't !
Of course .
Will you take that child home and then meet me back here in about an hour 's time ?
It 's all right .
It 's nearly dawn , she won 't leave the coffin again .
Is there no other way ?
But it 's horrible !
Please try and understand .
This is not Lucy , the sister you loved . It 's only a shell .
Possessed and corrupted by the evil of Dracula !
To liberate her soul and give it eternal peace , we must destroy that shell for all time !
Believe me , there is no other way .
( SCREAMING )
( MOANING )
- Drink this . - Oh , I 'm all right now .
- Drink it . - Thanks .
There 's so much in Jonathan 's diary I don 't understand .
Can Dracula really be as old as it says here ?
We believe it 's possible .
Vampires are known to have gone on from century to century .
Records show that Count Dracula could be 500 or 600 years old .
Another thing .
I always understood that , if there were such things ,
they could change themselves into bats or wolves .
That 's a common fallacy .
Holmwood , the study of these creatures has been my life 's work .
I 've carried out research with some of the greatest authorities in Europe .
And yet , we 've only just scratched the surface .
You see , a great deal is known about the vampire bat .
But details of these re-animated bodies of the dead ,
the " undead , " as we call them ,
are so obscure , that many biologists will not believe they exist .
Of course , you are shocked and bewildered .
How can you expect to understand in so short a time ?
But you 've read and experienced enough to know
that this unholy cult must be wiped out .
- I hope perhaps that you will help me . - I 'll do anything you say .
Thank you .
Of course , we do know certain things .
You witnessed one a little while ago .
And we also know that during the day the vampire must rest in his native soil .
Now .
When I went to Castle Dracula , a hearse came tearing through the gates .
In that hearse was a coffin .
I believe it contained Dracula and a bed of his own earth .
To get here , that hearse would have to come via the frontier at Ingstadt .
They 'll have a record there of where it was going .
We need that address . Will you come with me to Ingstadt ?
How long will it take ? I must let Mina know .
With any luck , we should be back by tomorrow morning .
( COUGHING )
I 'm afraid that is quite out of the question , sir . Against regulations .
All we want to know is where the coffin was going .
I can 't give away information without proper authority .
This is a matter of great urgency ! I am a doctor .
I 'm sorry , sir .
There 's a young lad with a message for you .
Personal , he said . He wouldn 't give it to me .
All right , Gerda , I 'll see him .
- Yes ? - You Mrs Holmwood ?
- I am . - Got a message for you .
You 're to go to 49 Frederickstrasse right away , he says .
And you 're not to tell anyone .
Who says ?
Arthur Holmwood , he calls himself . Said you 'd know him .
But that 's impossible . My husband has gone to Ingstadt .
Not if he gave me this message , he hasn 't . And he gave me this message .
Good night .
You 've got to have permission from the Ministry in writing .
I have my orders and I must obey them .
It is laid down in the government regulations that under no circumstances ...
Under no circumstances may an unauthorized person be permitted to examine .
Of course , in the case of an emergency , we do sometimes make an exception .
And seeing this gentleman is a doctor ...
( COUGHING )
- When did you say it was , sir ? - December 1 .
December 1 . Klausenburg to Karlstadt . Let me see .
Here it is . One hearse , one coffin .
J. Marx , 49 Frederickstrasse , Karlstadt .
( RINGING DOORBELL )
MINA : Arthur ?
Arthur ?
( SUSPENSEFUL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
Are you sure I can 't get you anything to eat , sir ?
No , thank you , Gerda . We haven 't time .
But I would like a word with Mrs Holmwood before we go .
- Will you go up and see if she 's awake yet ? - Yes , sir .
Are you ready ?
- She 's not there , sir . - Not there ?
GERDA : No , sir .
MINA : Good morning .
Mina , you gave me quite a fright .
Where have you been at this hour of the morning ?
It was such a lovely day , I got up early and went for a walk in the garden .
- I didn 't expect you back so soon . - I 'm afraid I 've to go out again .
- Oh . When will you be back ? - I can 't say for sure .
Mina , you look pale . Are you all right ?
Arthur , darling , don 't fuss . I feel perfectly well .
Goodbye , darling .
( DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES )
Perhaps you 'd better let me lead the way , I know these steps , they can be dangerous .
We don 't want to have an accident , do we ? No , we don 't .
You know , an old man came here once to see his dear departed
and he fell down these stairs . ( LAUGHS ) It was quite amusing .
He came to pay his last respects and he remained to share them .
( LAUGHING ) Oh , quite amusing .
Where are we ? Where are we ? Where are we ?
It 's around the back , somewhere .
It 's been here so long it 's bound to be at the back , isn 't it ?
Come on , this way , gentlemen . You follow me .
I know where it was . This way .
There 's an extraordinary thing !
It was there . I know it was , because I saw it only yesterday .
I really don 't understand who could have moved it .
The driver of the hearse might 've lied to the Frontier Official
about where he was going .
Yes , but that fellow at the morgue wasn 't lying .
He was really surprised when he saw the coffin wasn 't there .
He must have had it sometime .
- I think he 's still somewhere here in Karlstadt . - But where ? This is a big town .
There are not many places he can hide , don 't forget .
There is that , of course .
What are you two being so mysterious about over there ?
We 'll be with you in a moment , my darling .
There is an old neglected graveyard about three miles from here .
Somewhere in this area .
St Joseph 's .
Just one moment .
Mina , my dear , don 't think I 'm being silly ,
but I 'd feel much happier , if during my absence , you would wear this for me .
Please don 't ask me why , but just wear it for my sake .
- Arthur , I ... - Please , Mina .
( GASPING )
( DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
You said Lucy would lead us to Dracula . Why didn 't I listen to you ?
This would never have happened .
You mustn 't blame yourself for that ,
but you must have the courage to let Mina lead us now .
We 'll give her every protection we can .
Tonight we 'll watch the windows of her room .
- They face two sides of the house , don 't they ? - Yes .
I know I ask a great deal of you , but you mustn 't weaken now .
We have it within our power to rid the world of this evil .
And , with God 's help , we 'll succeed .
( WOLF HOWLING )
( SINISTER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( SUDDEN SCREECHING )
Mina 's safe now , but we must keep watch again tonight . You 'd better get some rest .
- What about you ? - I 'll be all right in there , if I may .
Right .
- I 'll get you a rug from our room . - Thank you .
ARTHUR : Mina !
( FRANTIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
Just sit still like that for a minute .
Thank you .
- Will she be all right ? - I think so .
Let me see your arm .
Steady .
Are you all right ?
Yes . Yes , it 's very good .
Now , you 'll need plenty of fluid . Tea , coffee or , better still , wine .
Go down and have some now , there 's a good fellow .
Don 't worry , Gerda and I will take care of her .
Just bathe her forehead , will you , Gerda ? With eau de cologne or something .
Yes , sir .
- How is she now ? - She 's reacted very well .
Thank God !
How did he get in ? We watched the house all night .
Your theory must be wrong . He can change into something else .
He must be able to . How else could he have got in ?
I wish I knew .
- Madam is sleeping now , sir . - She mustn 't be left .
I 'll go up to her . I 'd like to .
You stay and rest , and have some wine . I 'm sure you need both .
- Gerda , will you fetch another bottle ? - Oh , sir , I don 't like to .
You know what happened last time when I disobeyed Mrs Holmwood 's orders .
What do you mean ?
Well , sir , Madam told me the other day that I must , on no account , go down to the cellar .
( FAST-PACED INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( HISSES )
Holmwood ! Holmwood !
Holmwood !
( GERDA SCREAMING )
( GERDA WAILING )
Gerda , what happened ?
You said I was to come back to Madam , so I came up here .
- And he looked like the devil ! - Gerda ! Now , what happened ?
He came in here and he picked Madam up like she was a baby !
Calm yourself , Gerda . Calm yourself .
There 's only one place he can make for now . His home .
It 's a coach driver . He 's been dead about half an hour .
You think Dracula killed that coachman ?
Of course he did . Without a coach he 'd never get home before sunrise .
He 'd be dead .
- But even if he does get home ... - He 'd hide in the castle vaults for years .
- We 'd lose him there . - And Mina ?
( HORSES NEIGHING )
- ( CRASHING ) - ( GASPS )
Oh !
Hey ! ( COUGHING )
Halt !
( LOUD CRASH )
It 's getting light .
( DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( SCREAMS )
ARTHUR : Whoa !
Look !
( FAST-PACED INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( BOTH GRUNTING )
( SCREAMING )
( GASPING )
( MOANING )
( SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )
( SOLEMN INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC )